檢查一下，你還記得這個嗎？
Check Do you remember this?
你還得再回答一次。
And you'll have to answer that again.
因為在我們的大腦裡
Because in our brains
真正形成那些連結的就是這個，
that's what's really like forming those connections,
我們的神經連結，
our neural connections
實際上幫助我們記住這些概念。
and actually helping us remember these concepts.
我認為學習模式真的
And I think that study mode does a really
非常適合你想要真正學會一個概念，
great job if you really want to learn a concept
並且應用該概念，充分理解它的全部潛力。
and apply that concept and understand it to its fullest potential.
這時候你就會用它，
That's when you would use it
而不是只想要一個問題的答案。
when you don't want just a question answer.
是的，
Yeah,
我也做過類似的
I've also kind of done like a similar like
並排比較學習模式和一般模式，
side-by-side comparison with study mode versus like the regular mode
我覺得非常有分析性。
and I think very analytical.
我很喜歡這個。
I love this.
我玩得像是，喔
I played like, Oh
這真的很酷。
this is pretty cool.
我想當時我正在
And I think like when I so I was
我想我當時是在嘗試。
I think I was like trying to.
我在做一個非常小眾主題的研究，
I was doing like a research on a very like niche topic,
關於電子舞曲和狂歡文化的。
kind of about like EDM and rave culture.
還有它在加州的歷史。
And it's like history in like California.
我當時想，
And I was like
我覺得這是一個非常有趣的主題，
I feel like that's like a really interesting topic
可以研究看看，了解一下。
to kind of do research on and see what.
你知道的，看看ChatGPT怎麼說，我記得，嗯
Like, you know, chat GBT has to say about it, and I remember, well
我想我用ChatGPT做研究的方式是，
I guess my usage of like kind of chat GBT for like research is.
我覺得我總是
I feel like I always
心裡一直有個念頭
in the back of my mind
承認它就像一個大型語言模型。
acknowledging that it's like an LLM.
不太適合用於研究，除非
Not very like suited for like research unless
你對它有良好的參數設定。
you kind of have good parameters around it.
所以我通常的做法是
So usually the way I approach it is
先瀏覽我找到的資料來源，
that I go through my sources that I find,
像是透過Google，找研究論文。
like through Google, like research papers.
然後我會把它貼到聊天視窗裡，
And I actually paste that into the chat
並要求它只從那些參數中提取資訊。
and ask it to only draw from those parameters.
因為我想讓內容更具體，不那麼泛泛而談。
Because I want to keep it like, more contained and less like general.
所以我覺得
And so I feel like
當我在做那種研究，像是探討
when I was doing that research into like, kind of looking into like
加州的電子舞曲文化時，我發現。
rave culture in California, I found that.
當我使用一般模式並輸入相關背景時，
Like, when I use the regular mode and put in the context
它確實產生了不錯的結果，
it did produce a good output
但使用穩定模式時
but with steady mode
我其實根本不需要用到那個上下文
I didn't even really need to use that context
因為它把範圍縮小到那種來回對話的參數。
because it narrowed the parameters to that back-and-forth chat.
我覺得我的學習在那裡變得更嚴謹了。
And I feel like my learning was more kind of rigorous through there.
因為我們是在回答問題，
Because it's like we're answering questions instead
而不是被灌輸，
of being like Fed,
就像是一些內容片段，
kind of like pieces of content
是一般模式提供的資訊。
information that the regular mode gave.
所以我覺得那是一種非常有效的學習方法。
So I thought that was like a really effective kind of learning method.
這是否讓你對未來更有信心，
Has this given you more confidence about the
在尋找職位方面，
future as far as you're finding a role
以及能否適應接下來的變化？
and being able to adapt to whatever is going to come next or not?
我覺得，絕對是的，
Definitely, I think,
我認為OpenAI所產出的東西有兩面向。
I think there's two sides to to what OpenAI is producing.
我覺得這個代理模式，
I think with this like agent mode there
有一種超未來感，讓你會想，
there is that like super futuristic look where you think,
喔，像是，可能有些，像是
oh, like, maybe some, like
我以前實習時做過的某些任務
certain tasks that I used to be doing for my internship
他們甚至不會想讓我做。
they won't even want me to do.
但使用學習模式時
But then with study mode
就像是回頭思考，像是
it's really like drawing it back and thinking about, like
你在學校學到的每個概念。
each concept that you're learning in school.
所以對我來說
And so, to me
我認為學習模式是 Chat GPT 中最重要的模式之一
I think study mode is one of the most important modes in in Chat GPT
因為它真的能幫助你學習。
because it'll actually help you learn.
而我覺得人們通常是
Whereas I think people are
當他們嘗試使用 AI 時
when they're trying to use AI
他們只是想直接得到答案。
they're trying to just get the answer.
是的，所以，我
Yeah, so yeah, I'm.
我很期待。
I'm excited.
作為一個終身學習者，每次我們有
As a lifelong learner is every time we have
像這樣的新工具，可以不斷地玩弄它
a new tool like this to continuously play with it
然後看看它會發展到哪裡
and then to see where this is heading
我一直在使用 Chat GPT。
I use Chat GPT all the time.
我在這裡坦承這點
I'm gonna admit that here
我不會花太多時間在社群媒體上
I don't spend a lot of time on social media
但我從來不是那種重度社群
but it's never really big social
媒體使用者，除了看新聞之外。
media person other than like for news.
你的經驗是什麼？
What has been your experience?
你會花時間嗎？
Do you spend?
像是，怎麼花？
Like, how?
平常一天是怎麼過的？
is like, what's a normal day for you?
還有，像是
And then also like
假設你用多少時間在社群媒體，跟 Chat GPT 比較起來？
let's say how much social media are using versus chat?
GPT。
GPT.
對我來說，我想是這樣。
For me, I think so.
其實我不是最近才這樣
I actually not recently
大約是一年前，
about like a year ago,
我決定稍微遠離社群媒體的使用。
kind of decided to take a step back from social media usage.
特別是像抖音這類的，
Just particularly like tick-tock
因為我覺得自己每天都在接收
just cuz I feel like I was just like getting
大量集中在同一個地方的內容，
a lot of content in one place in like a day
以一種容易消化的方式，
like a digestible manner
這也是它方便的地方。
which is like what the convenience of it is.
但我覺得我開始過度依賴這種便利性。
But I feel like I started getting too used to that convenience.
而且，我覺得，
And like, like, I feel like.
我只是，
I was just like,
有點被動地消費內容，卻沒有真正
kind of passively consuming content without really
去研究或查證它。
like researching or fact-checking it as much.
我覺得這樣不太好。
I feel like it wasn't.
這不就是抖音的重點嗎，對啊。
That's the whole point of tick-tock, yeah
這就是重點。
that's the whole point.
但我覺得它讓我變得相當自滿。
But like, I feel like I was like it was making me pretty complacent.
我想，是的，我不喜歡那樣。
I think, yeah, and I didn't like that
所以我決定戒掉它。
so I decided to go off it.
嗯，所以從那個角度來看，
Um, so in that sense
我覺得我較少使用影片類型的內容，
I think less of usage with like video form content
但我喜歡用社群媒體和同儕溝通，
but I do like you social media to like communicate with my peers,
你知道的，
and you know
我想Instagram主要是用來分享照片之類的。
I guess Instagram for like photos and stuff like that.
但我覺得ChatGPT在我生活中變得更重要了。
But I think chat GPT has become more salient in my life.
因為我覺得現在作為學生，
Like, cuz I feel like right now as a student.
我的生活有80%都在學校，
Like, like 80% of my life is like school
甚至連暑假也是，
and then I guess even the summer,
我的生活有另外80%都在工作。
like another 80% of my life is like work.
所以我覺得我確實會使用它。
So I feel like I definitely use it
無論是在那方面，
whether it's like in terms of that,
甚至是日常生活中的活動。
or even like day-to-day like activities.
我覺得我用ChatGPT的頻率遠高於社群媒體。
I feel like much more using chat GPT than I am social media.
是啊，沒錯。
But yeah, yeah.
我認為一個很重要的點是，
I think a big thing is that, like
社群媒體現在試圖成為那種
social media is now trying to be that kind of
一站式的綜合平台，
like a one-stop shop for kind of everything,
對吧？
right?
現在人們會在社群媒體上購物，
Like, people will now shop on social media
也會在社群媒體上獲取新聞，
people will now find their news on social media
看看朋友們在做什麼。
see what their friends are doing.
我覺得，跟你說的類似，這就是關於
And I think, similar to what you were saying, yeah, be about like
你如何使用社群媒體，
how social media you
你開始接觸到各種不同的內容。
you kind of started getting a little bit of everything.
有些人覺得這是好事，但對我來說，
You know, some people can find that as a good thing, but for me
以前我使用社群媒體時，
when I used to go on social media
我發現自己會滑動好幾個小時。
I realized that I was just scrolling for hours.
因為我覺得，喔，像是
Because I realized that I was like, oh, like
我正在獲取一些新聞內容，
I'm getting some news content
我也在這裡學習一些事情。
I'm learning about some things here.
所以我對於
And so I was less actual
自己花在社群媒體上的時間，並沒有真正意識到。
actually conscious about the time I was spending on social media.
我發現那段時間裡，很多內容
And I realized that a lot of that time is
其實是我不想看的。
just a lot of content that I don't want as well.
所以我意識到，對我日常生活來說，
And so I've realized that that, you know, for my day-to-day I
我減少了使用社群媒體的時間，
I've drawn back on my social media usage
在學習和探索想法方面，
and when it comes to learning and exploring ideas.
我會向 Chat GPT 提出很多問題，
I ask Chat GPT a lot of those questions
因為我對自己想要的東西非常明確，
because I'm very specific about what I want
以及我能從 Chat GPT 獲得什麼。
and what I can get out of chat, GPT.
還有社群媒體。
And social media.
我有意識地把它當作休閒時間使用，
I I use consciously is like my leisure time,
就是放鬆一下，享受一些內容。
just like relax and just enjoy some content.
而且，我不會
Whereas, like, I don't
喜歡把所有東西都混在同一個應用程式裡。
I don't like to kind of mix everything into one app.
對我來說，有這麼一刻，
For me, there was this moment
那真的是在深入研究時發生的，
and it really happened with deep research
我得到的資訊品質，
where the quality of things I was
常常比我在網路上找到的還要好。
getting was often better than I found online.
我發現，
And I found it like
我可以提出一個非常有趣的問題，
I could ask a really interesting question.
可能是關於一些愚蠢的事情，比如說，
It'd be something silly about, like, you know
一群鱷魚屠殺人類之類的，我是說，
a bunch of crocodiles massacring people or something like, I mean
還有一個二戰的故事。
there's a World War Two story.
我會想，這到底是真相是什麼？
I'm like, what's the truth about this?
你會得到一份深入的研究報告，並且回覆得很好。
And you get a deep research report and comes back well.
我當時反應過度了，
I was overblown,
但瀏覽這些資料並說，好的，這很有趣，
but that was fun to sort of look through these things and say, Okay
我想要的是什麼問題？
what are questions I want that?
我希望有相關的文章。
I wish there are articles on that?
你有沒有發現，突然之間，
And and did you find that, too, that all of a sudden?
內容變得更好了。
Content got better.
我記得在高中時，
I remember so in high school
當 ChatGPT 剛推出的時候，
when when Chad GPT first came out
我正在上一門研究課，
I was in like a research like a research class.
基本上我就是研究我想要的主題，
Where I basically just researched on a topic that I wanted to.
然後
And
and
寫了一篇論文。
wrote a paper about it.
一開始，ChatGPT 無法連接網路，
And early on, Chad GPT couldn't access the web
所以我會貼上一個連結，然後想，喔
so I'd paste in a link and be like, Oh
我看不懂那個。
I can't read that.
所以我發現，
And so I found that like
我會像是放入一篇很長的論文，
I would like pace like a big paper in
然後試著用那種方式給它資料，
and and try to give it that way
但結果並不是這樣。
but it wasn't.
它不擅長，像是
It wasn't good at, like
幫我找內容，
finding content for me
所以我真的得自己去做這件事。
so I really had to do that myself.
不過深度研究，
But deep research,
它能讓我找到符合我需求的特定內容。
it could allow me to actually find content specific to what I want.
我通常會告訴它，
And what I usually do is I tell it
只搜尋真正學術性的，
to only only search for really academic,
有實證支持的研究，並且形成論點。
merit-backed, like research and formulate an argument.
對我來說，內容本身其實非常好。
For me, and the content itself is actually very good
我經常引用它。
and I cite it pretty often.
那麼對你來說，Abby
So for you, Abby
你有什麼特別的技巧嗎
do you have any particular tricks you use
或者你會做些什麼來嘗試讓它
or things you do to try to get it
以你想要的方式運作？
to sort of perform the way you want it to?
嗯，我想，首先也是最重要的
Um, I think, yeah, first and foremost
就是縮小研究的範圍
kind of like narrowing the research
我覺得透過提供特定的參數很有幫助
parameters I think is helpful by feeding
讓它從我想要的資料來源生成內容。
it kind of the sources that I want it to kind of generate from.
然後我覺得對我來說
And then I think for me
我也會讓它扮演批判者的角色。
I also prompt it to be a critical actor.
有時候，因為我覺得
Sometimes because I think, like
儘管我很喜歡
as much as I like
我收到的回饋，特別是說
kind of the feedback I receive, especially, say so
比方說我在腦力激盪研究論文的時候，對吧？
say if I'm like, trying to brainstorm, like a research paper, right?
我當時心想
And I'm like
在構思我的論文主旨陳述，並且
formulating like my kind of thesis like statement and having,
整理我的重點。
like, my set points.
我覺得我收到的回饋
And I think the feedback I get,
大多數都是非常正面的。
for the most part is like, overwhelmingly positive.
是的，那是大家對它的第一反應
Yeah, and that's like the first, I mean, reaction to it
我認為這是合理的。
and I think that's that's valid.
但有時我希望能有真正批判性的觀點。
But sometimes I want an actual critical like outlook.
所以我覺得引導它去
So I think prompting it to kind
扮演特定角色非常有幫助。
of embody certain personas is really helpful.
它給出的回應能夠實際上做出一篇
And like the response that it gives to actually make a like,
完整的論文。
a holistic like paper.
然後我覺得把這個和，像是，
And then I think coupling that, like, with, you know
請教授協助
like having your professors help
並且填補某些空白，會很有幫助。
and kind of also filling certain gaps, I think helps.
像是要有一個整體的概覽。
Like, have a holistic kind of overview.
至少當我在寫作時是這樣。
At least when I'm writing people.
所以給我們一些你如何提示的例子，
So give us some example of how you prompt
當你談到
when you talk about
不同的角色時，
like a different personas
你具體會要求它做什麼。
what you ask it to do specifically.
舉例來說，
So, for example,
我想之前我做過一些關於陰謀論的研究，
I think a while back I was doing some research on conspiracy theories
我覺得那是很有趣的研究。
and I think it was it was interesting research.
所以我覺得外面有很多資訊，
So I feel like there's a lot of information out there
所以我認為第一步，肯定是縮小那些範圍。
and so I think first step, definitely narrowing those parameters.
然後我想我在創造一些論點，
And then I think I was creating kind of the arguments that like
接著我請它做的。
followed under there and I asked it.
嗯，我請它實際編造一個陰謀論，
Um, I asked it to actually make up a conspiracy theory
利用我一直在學習的概念，
using kind of the concepts that I've been learning,
所以它編造了一個陰謀論。
and so it made up a conspiracy theory.
那個理論是什麼？
What was the theory?
我想那是一個關於……的理論，
I think it was some theory about like
機場的鏡子怎麼運作，
airport mirrors go on
但我忘了具體細節是什麼，
and I forgot what the exact parameters were
大概是說機場的鏡子是怎麼樣的。
but it was something about how like airport mirrors are.
像是，
Like,
監視你的行動，提醒你要小心。
monitoring like your activity and how like you should be careful.
但它顯然用很優雅的方式表達，
But it obviously worded it in very elegant way
因為它利用了那類研究，來說明，
because it was using kind of that research to kind of like, say, okay
這就是人們相信它的原因。
this is why people believe in it.
所以我請它扮演不同角色，
And so I asked it to take up like certain personas across,
例如政治光譜上的角色，然後問它，
like, for example, the political scale, and ask it.
你知道，這個人會怎麼反應，
Like, you know, how would this person react to it
這個人會怎麼批評它。
how would this person critique it
這個人怎麼會相信這個呢？
how would this person believe in it?
我覺得它給了我一個大致的概覽，
And I think it gave me, like, kind of like an overview,
不只是學習，也幫助我形成論點。
like for my learning, but also like for the like argument forming.
確保我從這個角度思考，
Making sure that I'm thinking it from like,
用批判的視角或其他視角。
this critical lens or this lens.
而不是只做，像是
And not just do, like
我認為你對那個陰謀論所知道的事。
what I think you know about that conspiracy theory.
那真的很棒。
That's really good.
我覺得這是其中一個很容易被忽略的事情，
I think that that's one of the really low key things
我認為大家可以多做的，不只是說，
I think people could probably do more of is not just say
只給一個觀點，而是實際說出，像是，
give it one point of view, but actually tell, like, yeah
給我幾個不同的觀點。
give me a couple different points of view.
那就是你用 GPT-3 的時候。
And that was you back with GPD 3.
我覺得那真的很酷，因為
That was what I thought was really cool as
我可以模擬不同觀點的對話。
I could simulate a conversation from different points of view.
閱讀那些逐字稿很有趣
And it was reading those transcripts was interesting
因為你可以看到模型相當擅長適應這些內容。
because you could see the models pretty good at adapting to that.
我喜歡拿研究論文來說，
And I love taking research papers and saying
給我反方觀點，
give me the counterpoint
給我這個對那個，
give me this to that
我認為作為這樣的工具，
and I think as that kind of tool,
這是很有幫助的。
that's helpful.
你有沒有特別的
Do you have any particular kind of
技巧用於任何角色設定，
tips you use for any kind of personas
或是你會問的某些問題？
or any to some questions you ask?
是的，絕對如此，我同意
Yeah, definitely, I agree with like
它對你非常寬容，
the it's very like, lenient with you
它會像是，喔，
and it'll be like, oh, like
你在這方面做得很好，
you've done a great job on this
我發現你可以在那裡。
and I found that there you can.
你可以為你的聊天設定具體指示
You can put a specific instructions for your chat
所以如果你進入個人化 GPT
so if you go to like Personalized GPT
你可以輸入具體的指示。
you can put specific instructions.
我會說，不要廢話，直接切入重點。
So I say, like, no fluff, like, just get to the point.
每當我問你問題時，請對我坦誠以待。
Be brutally honest with me whenever I
無論是我提問還是提交內容時。
ask you a question or whenever I submit.
還有關於角色設定的部分。
What I have, and to the persona thing as well.
像是，
Like,
我覺得這是一件很棒的事，
I think it's it's a great thing to to
能獲得不同的觀點，而不是只告訴它，
get different perspectives versus just tell it,
喔，
oh
你覺得怎麼樣？
what do you think?
因為那樣它會更像是，
Because then it'll be, oh, like, more like
我會站在你的立場和觀點上。
I'll take your side and your perspective on it.
所以我告訴它，知道嗎，
So I've, I've told it to, you know
扮演頂尖公司的顧問角色
act as like a like a consultant at a top firm
告訴我你是怎麼做到的。
and tell me how you do this.
或者我叫她扮演一位非常有創意的
Or I told her to act as like a super creative
專門研究這個領域的教授
like professor that researches on this
並提出獨特的解決方案。
and come up with unique solutions to this.
所以我覺得我真的在
So I think I'm really putting putting
賦予ChatGPT一個角色或視角。
chat GPT into like a persona or perspective.
而且專業人士會
And a professional will like
讓它能夠表現得更好，這是我注意到的。
empower it to actually do better is what I've noticed.
我覺得你們兩個都是非常投入的學生。
You two are both, I think, probably very well engaged students.
你們對這件事有很多想法。
You, you, you have a lot of thought about this.
你聽過哪些誤解？
What are some misconceptions you hear?
像是我跟人談到在教育中使用ChatGPT，
Like, I talk to people, bring a chat, GPT in education?
大家會說有人用它作弊之類的，然後
People got cheating and this sort of stuff, and again
這裡面確實有值得討論的話題。
there's a conversation to be had for there.
但我覺得有時候我會聽到這樣的假設
But I think sometimes I hear this assumption
認為每個孩子都會自動用這個來作弊。
that every kid's just automatically going to use this to cheat.
你有遇過這種情況嗎？
Have you encountered that?
你覺得，嗯，
Do you feel like, you know
這是你經驗中會發生的事嗎？
was that a in your experience?
這是一個很好的問題，
It is a great question
這個問題需要很多思考。
and there's a lot of thought that goes into it.
但我越想關於原創性，
But the more I think about kind of originality
以及人們如何想要你自己真實且原創的作品。
and how how people want like your own authentic, original work.
因為這樣會幫助你的學習。
Because like, that'll help with your learning.
這點絕對沒錯。
That's that's definitely true.
但我們會到達一個關於 AI 的階段，
But then we're gonna get to a point with AI
也許我們已經到了，
maybe we already have
而且這趨勢會持續下去。
but it'll keep going down the line.
屆時，AI 產出的作品會變成像是，
Where actually, like, AI produced work is going to be like,
比人類好上許多許多。
much, much better than than humans.
到了這種程度，
To the point where
我們為什麼還要輕忽 AI 所能產出的成果？
why are we just like dismissing what what an AI can produce?
我認為很快我們就會達到這個階段，
And I think soon we'll get to the point
像 ChatGPT 這樣的工具會有
where we'll have chat GPT like it'll have a
更大的影響力，比方說，
much bigger impact and let's say,
用來撰寫報告。
like writing some report.
但老師們也會
But then teachers will
以及學生們也必須適應
and students will also have to adapt
如何展現他們的成長。
to how they can show their growth.
同時也要充分利用 AI，
While also like using AI to its fullest
因為它能完成許多人體無法做到的任務。
because it can complete so many great tasks that humans can't.
我覺得這個問題很難回答，
I think it's it's just hard to answer that question
因為我覺得我們正在重新定義。
because I feel like we're redefining.
不，他剛剛說這是個很棒的問題。
No, he just said it was a great question.
他剛剛說這是個好問題。
He just said it was a good question.
我只是想說
I was just saying
我覺得這真的很難
I think it's just it's hard
因為我覺得我們好像在重新定義，像是
because I feel like we're like kind of redefining, we're like.
作弊的意義，
Cheating means,
所以我覺得我甚至不知道作弊到底是什麼意思了。
so I feel like I don't even know what cheating means anymore.
所以我覺得這就是為什麼會
So I feel like that's why it's like,
有點困難。
kind of hard.
是的，不，
Yeah, no,
這是一個合理的問題，也是一個合理的回答。
it's a fair question and a fair response.
你會給高中生什麼建議
What advice would you give to high
關於現在使用這些工具？
school students right now about using these tools?
我不知道，我想我有件事，像是
I don't know something that I think I've, like
很多朋友都在討論的。
a lot of my friends were talking about.
甚至在我來這裡之前，我也，知道嗎
Even like before I came, came here, I was, you know
和大學的朋友們待在一起
staying with my friends from college
我們就在聊著一些事情。
and we were just like talking about.
我在問他們關於 Chat GPT 和人工智慧的經驗
I was asking their experiences about like, Chat GPT and AI
其中一個朋友說
and one of my friends was like
我覺得如果高中時有 Chat GPT 的話
I feel like if I had Chat GPT in high school
我現在不會有今天的成就。
I wouldn't be where I am today.
我問她說，喔
And I asked her, like, Oh
你這話是什麼意思？她說
what do you mean by that? and she said
我覺得我會變得更笨。
I feel like I would just be stupider.
我覺得她這樣說得最貼切
I feel like that's just the best way she put it
所以我就思考了這件事。
and so I thought about that.
我覺得我多少能理解她的觀點。
And I feel like I can somewhat see that point.
但我認為人工智慧的發展方式
But I think the way that, like AI, is developing
至少在人工智慧的使用上
at least AI usage
我覺得我們已經開始注意到了。
I feel like we're noticing.
至少從經驗來看，這有點像是一種轉變
Kind of like a shift, at least, you know, anecdotally
從我所見，是一種轉變，逐漸遠離
from what I see, a shift away from.
不再把它當作作弊的工具，或者說
Kind of using it as like a cheat use case, or, you know
用來走捷徑的用途
a use case to like, you know, take the easier path,
而是更多用來提升
but more so to just like, improve,
你的生產力和學習效率
like your productivity, and like, learning.
我認為，從這個角度來看
And I think, like, through that lens
我覺得那個建議
I think that advice
是我會給出的
like I would give
就是要有內在的動力
is to kind of, like, you know, have like an intrinsic motivation.
這說起來不容易
I mean, that's hard advice
但我覺得你知道的
but I feel like, you know
你必須有學習的動機
you just have like that motivation to learn.
我認為你可以善用 Chat GPT 來幫助你
And I think you can really use Chat GPT to kind of help you
但同時不要把它當成拐杖依賴
but don't use it as a crutch at the same time.
我覺得你必須對自己負責。
I think you just have to hold yourself accountable.
不要只是用它來取得答案，
And kind of not using it to get the answer
而是用來幫助你更好地理解事物。
and more so to help you kind of understand things better.
但我覺得這很難，
But I think that's that's hard
尤其是在你還是高中生的時候。
when you're in high school.
不過我認為這能讓你穿越雜音，
But I think it allows you to kind of cut through the noise
去做你真正喜歡的事，而不是，
and do things that you actually enjoy versus, you know
那些被分配給你的事情。
things that are kind of like, assigned to you.
是的，絕對如此。
Yes, yeah, definitely.
我想對現在的高中生說，要保持警惕。
I'd say for high school students right now, I'd say, be wary.
我在這段時間裡注意到了這點。
I've noticed that throughout my time.
我的意思是，我是在高中開始接觸這些的，
I mean, I started learning about in high school
我確實看到了其中的危險。
and I definitely saw the dangers of it.
因為自滿和習慣了它，做了所有那些事情。
With complacency and getting used to it, doing all the things.
然後當你
And then when you
當你真正面對考試時
when you actually get to the test
當你真正挑戰自己所學的時候
and when you actually get to challenge what you've learned
你會發現自己掌握的知識變少了。
you have less of that knowledge.
但我注意到這幾個月來
But I've noticed that these past few months
我真的把 Chat GPT 推到了極限
I've really kind of pushed Chat GPT to its limits
也把自己逼到了極限。
and pushed myself to my limits.
我發現自己能完成的事情比以前多得多。
And I've noticed that I can accomplish a lot more than I used to.
我記得高中時我在做一個專案
I remember in high school I was I was working on some project
那是一個影像分類器專案。
it was a image classifier project.
我花了很長時間，閱讀大量文件才真正學會
And it took me a long time, a lot of documents to to actually learn
並了解如何完成這件事。
and understand how to do this.
但現在你可以
But now you can
利用 AI，實際上能更快完成這項工作。
you can utilize AI and actually get this done much faster.
還能改進並產出成果，
And improve on it and produce it
持續反覆優化，做出更好的產品。
and continue and and and iterate on it to make a much better product.
我會鼓勵高中生找到自己的熱情
And I would encourage high schoolers to to find a passion
並且真正投入其中
and and really dive into that
並且充分發揮它的價值
and and get the most out of it.
但同時
But at the same time
也要謹慎並堅持老師教導的概念
be wary and stick to the concepts that teachers are teaching you.
不要因為AI能幫你做就輕易否定它
And and don't just automatically dismiss it
因為AI可以替你完成
because AI can do it for you.
你希望老師現在怎麼教學？
How would you like teachers to be teaching now?
我認為，這是大膽的看法
I think, and and this is a bold take.
但我覺得最終我們會達到一個階段
But I think that eventually we're gonna get to a point
教育和講課完全由AI來完成
where we're education and the lectures are fully done by AI.
我認為所有的內容
I think all all the content that
我們自己學習的內容都會由AI提供
we're consuming ourselves will be given by AI.
因為我注意到，根據經驗
Because I've noticed, anecdotally
每個學生的學習方式都不同
that each student learns differently.
當人工智慧發展到某個階段時，
And once AI gets to a point
會有一種多模態系統，可以讓你視覺化事物。
where there's like a multimodal system where you can visualize things.
它還會提供你像是YouTube影片，
And and it'll provide you, like YouTube videos
這些影片都是它自己創造的。
that it creates itself.
我們將會到達一個階段，
We're gonna get to a point
學生能透過人工智慧學習得更好。
where students learn better through AI.
我認為老師屆時會更專注於社交方面，
And I think teachers will then be focused more on like the social,
社交技巧，
social skills,
社會資本、指導，以及如何使用人工智慧。
social capital, part of it, and mentorship, and how to use AI.
因為，
Because.
我想大家也都擔心工作問題。
I think everyone's worried about jobs as well.
但適應力是學生和
But adaptation is the new job security for for students and
想進入職場的新鮮人新的工作保障。
for up-and-coming people that are trying to enter the job market.
這讓我有點好奇，我認為
That's where I kind of wonder those I think
人工智慧在陪伴、輔導等方面有很棒的角色。
that AI has this great place as a companion, as tutor and whatnot.
很多教材在某種程度上取代了教科書。
And a lot of material kind of replace the textbook.
但你提到了「指導」這個詞。
But you brought up the word mentorship.
我只是覺得，
I just see.
就我個人而言，
Personally speaking,
能夠……對我來說非常有價值，
I think there's so much value to me be able to
去找一位電機工程師，
go to an electrical engineer that
他真的從事過電機工程的工作。
actually had an electrical engineering job.
你知道，
You know,
一位真正做過相關工作的電腦科學老師。
a computer science teacher who actually has done the work of it, too.
所以你覺得未來會是這樣嗎？
And so do you see that kind of a sort of the future is?
這個想法是，AI會是非常優秀的助教，
The idea is that the AI is the really good TA
也是教科書，
it's the textbook
它會做這類事情。
it's doing this sort of stuff.
但我想你還是希望人類能保持在核心位置。
But then you want to still keep humans in the center, I guess.
就教學和學習而言，
Like in terms of like, teaching and learning
我覺得教你的人顯然會影響你
I feel like obviously who teaches you
學到什麼以及你如何喜歡
impacts what you learn and how you like
在日後生活中應用它。
apply it on later on in life.
而且，我覺得你可以，你知道，
And like, I feel like you can, you know,
學習生物學中相同的概念，比如有絲分裂
learn the same concept in biology, like mitosis
概念是一樣的，但教你的人不同？
it's the same concept, but like, who teaches you?
這真的會改變很多，你知道嗎？
Like, kind of really changes that, you know?
所以我認為這就是學習中人性面向的所在，
So I think that's where the human aspect of, like
真正發揮作用的地方，
learning really comes in
也是讓學習變得重要的原因，
and it's what makes it important
我認為這就是人與人之間的連結。
and I think that human connection.
所以我覺得這有點像是，
So I think it's it's somewhat like
我想像的是，
I think I envision, like,
這兩者的某種混合體，
somewhat of like a hybrid kind of those two things
我們可以從人工智慧那裡獲得一個標準。
where I think we can get a standard from AI.
因為它很有幫助
Because it's helpful
因為它很簡單
because it's easy
因為它很容易接觸，然後有點這樣。
because it's like, you know, accessible, and then kind of.
那種指導的元素帶有個人觸感
That mentorship element comes in with the touch
還有你如何應用它
and like how you apply it
尤其是你如何從倫理角度思考它
and especially how you think about it in terms of ethics.
我想我們可能會開始轉變，遠離
I think maybe we'll start shifting away from
只是學習怎麼做，
just like learning how to do,
做、做，然後思考，像是
do, do and thinking about, like
這對人們有什麼影響？
how does this impact people?
你知道，我們如何透過這些技術幫助他人？
You know, how can we help others through these technologies?
我認為這種理解上的轉變
And I think that shift in understanding is
正是人性化觸感和指導會發揮作用的地方
where the human touch and mentorship will also come in.
所以我想，你知道
So I think, you know
擁有那種混合模式，真的
having that hybrid model is, you know
我對未來的某種想像
something that I envision for the future
這可能會非常成功。
and that's something that could be really successful.
你認為人工智慧的未來會走向何方？
Where do you see the future headed with AI?
當然，就像任何技術一樣，
Definitely, just like how any technology works,
明顯地會簡化許多工作。
just like simplifying a lot of tasks, obviously.
我想很多人可能會擔心
And I think a lot of people maybe are worried about
或是在思考人工智慧的意識問題
or are thinking about consciousness in AI
但我不認為
and I don't think
人工智慧在很長一段時間內會產生意識。
that AI will will generate consciousness for a long time.
但我認為未來，
But I think that like in the future, like,
對，就像部署，像是，
right, like deploying, like, you know, like.
某些公司已經開發出
Certain companies have already developed,
可部署的軟體工程師AI代理人，
like deployable software engineers as an AI agent,
但部署一個完整的單一代理人，
but like deploying, like, like a full, just like a one agent.
能夠協調軟體工程師的工作，
That'll orchestrate, like a software engineer,
行銷人員、設計師，還有很多角色。
a marketer, a designer, so many things.
我覺得未來就是朝那個方向發展。
I think I think that's where the future is going.
人類將會站在哪個位置。
Where humans stand in.
這點絕對是這樣。
That definitely like.
他們需要持續參與其中。
They'll need to, like, stay in the loop.
我認為單純放任
I think just letting
讓人工智慧自由發展是危險的，
letting AI go is is dangerous
而且在未來一段時間內也不切實際。
and it isn't feasible for for the upcoming future..
你覺得十年後你的工作會是什麼樣子？
What do you think your job is gonna look like 10 years from now?
我覺得會是，會是
I think it'll, it'll be
一個混合的狀態。
it'll be a mixed bag.
我想是因為我覺得
I think because I think
我的工作很大部分是對外、面對人的，
because my job is pretty like kind of external facing people facing
我覺得現在有種緊張感，
I think right now, kind of the tension.
或者說我看到的人工智慧使用者群體，
Or the tribe I see with like AI usage
在創意領域裡，大家常說，喔，像是
and like creative fields is like, oh, like
我不想讀那些像是由
I don't want to read something made by like,
ChatGBT 之類的東西寫的文章。
ChatGBT or like, you know.
而且很多人批評破折號的使用，
And it's like a lot of critique on like the usage of em dashes,
還有逗號的用法。
like the comma.
我也只想讀那些經過深入研究的文章。
I want, I only want to read things by by deep research, too.
我現在常用破折號，就是為了惹人生氣。
I use em dashes all the time now, just to annoy people.
是啊，所以，嗯，
Yeah, and so like, yeah
有很多人批評說，
there's like a lot of like kind of critique about people,
他們不想讀那些內容，
like not wanting to read content.
因為是 AI 生成的。
That's like AI generated and like.
我在社群媒體上看到這種情況，
I see that like on social media
我也在
I see that in like
比較小眾的社群裡看到，像是 Substack，
more niche communities like substack
我覺得我至少讀過十五篇 Substack 文章。
I feel like I've read like at least 15 substack articles
有點像是在批評「like」的用法，
like kind of bashing the uses of like,
還有破折號的使用。
em dashes.
是的，確實存在這種情況。
Yeah, it's there is.
反應很有趣，但對我來說，這讓人覺得
Reactions are interesting, but like to me, it puts.
我現在更重視自傳性質的內容。
I put more value now on autobiographical stuff.
如果有人寫的是那種任何人都能寫的普通東西，
If somebody's writing a generic thing that anything could rate,
你懂的，
you know
任何人都能創作出來，
could anything could create
那我就不會那麼在意了。
then I don't really care as much.
但如果有人是這樣的，
But if somebody's like
這是我做這件事的經驗，
here's my experience doing this
對我個人來說價值就高得多。
that has way more value to me personally.
這其實就是關於，
It's just really about like
我認為未來，
I think in the future
至少在行銷領域，
at least in like marketing
這大概就是在調和那種緊張感
it's like probably just navigating that tension
並觀察觀眾喜歡共鳴什麼。
and seeing like what audiences like kind of resonate to.
所以也許誰知道，五年後會怎樣。
So maybe who knows, in like five years.
我覺得人工智慧生成的內容可能會
I feel like AI generated content might
成為常態並被接受。
be like the norm and like acceptable.
而我們作為
And like us as like
行銷人員，正推動著
marketers are kind of like pushing in that
創意輸入，並且對此
creative input and for that,
也就是說，人工智慧生成的產出。
like, you know, AI generated output.
但我覺得那還是遙遠的未來。
But I feel like that's that's still long years ahead.
不過，
But.
你最大的恐懼是什麼？
What is your biggest fear?
我先說我的，好嗎？
I'll give you mine, okay
我認為這些是令人驚嘆的技術
I think these are incredible technologies
我覺得有些事情。
I think there's.
我認為每個人都有權利
I think everybody has the right to
以他們想要的方式來接近這件事。
kind of approach this however they want.
如果有人說我要花時間，花自己的時間，那也沒問題。
And if somebody says I'm taking time, my time, that's fine.
我擔心的是，我認為這裡有很多價值。
My concern is, I think there's a lot of value.
我覺得這是一個非常棒的學習工具，
I think it's incredible learning tool
而且我發現人們可以很快跟上進度。
and and I find that people can get up to speed very quickly.
花六個月時間學習這些東西，
In six months, I think six months time spending this stuff.
你就能進入一家公司，
You can then go into a company
並且能做很多事情，
and you can do a lot of how
像是創立公司和處理這些事。
you can create a company and do this stuff.
我擔心的是人們猶豫太多，
And my concern is that people are kind of hesitating too much.
不敢提出問題。
And not asking a question.
也許我們沒有做足夠的教學，
And maybe we're not doing enough to teach
或是沒有充分傳達我們所做的一切，
or communicate everything we're doing there
我擔心的是人們會錯失良機。
and I fear my fear is people missing out.
我有點持相反的看法。
I kind of have like a like, an opposite, opposite view.
我覺得也許特別是
I think that maybe maybe specifically
因為我正在加入這種教育，有些人
because I'm I'm inserting this education that some
會試著去
people will try to like,
找出繞過的方法。
find a way around.
像是所有傳統教育中關於 AI 的部分
Like everything that's traditionally education with AI
教育裡面有很多漏洞。
and there are a lot of loopholes within education.
我擔心的是
And my fear is that
你會進入職場，
that you'll you'll get to the to the job market.
而且基本上，面試你的人
And and essentially, you, the the people interviewing.
不會問你說，喔，
You are not gonna ask like, oh, like
如果你遇到這個問題，
if you get this question
你會怎麼用 AI 來解決？
how are you gonna put into AI and solve it?
因為 AI 可以解這個問題？
because AI can solve this question?
不管你有什麼傳統的程式設計題目。
Whatever traditional coding question that you have.
但他們真正尋找的是概念
But they're really looking for the concepts
以及你如何適應和解決問題
and for how you how you adapt and solve problems
因為他們也需要那種人性面向
because they need that human aspect as well
人性是不會消失的。
like humanity is not going away.
而我擔心的是，
And my fear is that that,
這種工具的使用會走得太遠。
like the use of this tool, is gonna go too far.
他們會意識到，傳統教育
Where they realize that, like traditional education,
仍然很重要，
is still important,
理解那些概念依然重要。
and understanding those concepts is still important.
之後想要回頭會很困難。
And it'll be hard to, like, backtrack from there.
對我來說，
For me, like,
我的擔憂來自於知識和真理
my fear component comes from a place more of like having.
集中在同一個地方。
Kind of like knowledge and truth centralized in one place.
我覺得這才是我更害怕的事，
I think that's what's more fearful for me
因為我認為現在我們擁有
because I think right now we have
沒有被承認，分散在許多不同的地方。
not acknowledged fragmented in so many different places.
我認為學習的美妙之處在於將每一塊拼圖
And I think the beauty of learning is like taking each of those pieces
拼湊成一個整體，像是
and putting it together in one kind of like,
為自己建立一個流暢的理解。
streamlined understanding for yourself.
但我認為，隨著你知道的，
But I think with, you know,
像是使用 ChatGBT 和某些
kind of the usage of like ChatGBT and like certain,
你知道的，像聊天機器人這類的工具。
like, you know, like chatbots on its own.
還有那種搜尋引擎的功能。
And having that kind of like the search engine.
或者說是資訊的集中化。
Or like the centralization of truth.
我覺得這有時候可能會形成一個惡性循環，
I feel like could be like a bad feedback loop sometimes
因為你可能一直引用相同的來源，
where I think you're referring to the same sources
而沒有真正去努力
and not really doing kind of that work to like,
接觸不同的知識來源。
reach out different, like knowledge sources.
所以我想這就是我擔心的原因，
So I think that's where my fear comes from
而且我覺得當你知道的時候，這種擔憂會被放大。
and I think it becomes amplified when, like, you know
隨著出現一些特定的事物。
with emergence of things where they're like, specific.
比如說。
Like.
像這樣的聊天機器人會有特定主題，可能是，
Chatbots like that are themed so like, maybe,
你知道的，做一個聊天機器人。
like, you know, doing like a chatbot.
只針對，
Only for, you know,
極右派活動家，或者是極少數的活動家。
far far-right activists, or like far less activists.
然後，當你，
And like, kind of, when you, you know
陷入那種反饋循環，
go down those like feedback loops
無法抽身並擁有，
and you're unable to kind of extract yourself and have, like,
更廣闊的視角，因為某種程度上能接觸到，
a broader perspective because of kind of accessibility of,
你知道的，生成式人工智慧。
like, you know, generative AI.
我想這就是我恐懼的來源，某種程度上
I think is like where my fear comes from, so kind of
就像我們的社群媒體一樣，
like where our social media
你的恐懼是回音室效應。
your fear is kind of echo chambers.
人們只會說我只用這些來源或那些來源。
That people are gonna say I'm only use these sources or that sources.
我會說我很樂觀
I would say that I'm optimistic
總體來說很樂觀，因為這變得容易多了。
and overall optimistic because I it's a lot easier.
就像你之前指出的，你說，嘿
Like you pointed out before, as you said, hey
我希望你使用這些資源
I want you to use these sources
我希望你接受不同的意見，我就是這麼想。
and I want you to take different opinions and I want that.
這是不是我們需要思考的事情
And is that something we need to be thinking about
將更多融入教育中，
incorporating more into education and
以及我們如何教導人們批判性思考？
how we teach people critical thinking?
如果你不挑戰自己這個想法，
The idea that if you're not challenging yourself
你肯定無法學習，我百分之百同意這點。
you're not learning for sure, I 100% agree with that
我認為這正是學習模式做得很好的地方，
and I think that that's what the study mode does great
它確實給你帶來挑戰的元素。
like it does give you that challenging aspect.
當你的大腦開始，像是，你知道，
And when your brain starts, like, you know
真正深入探究，
really like diving deep
並開始進行批判性思考，
and you start thinking critically,
思考可能的不同反例，
thinking about maybe different counterexamples,
不同的觀點。
different perspectives.
這樣你就能獲得完整的整體
Then you can get a full overall
評估，等待
just assessment of wait
無論你想思考什麼。
whatever you want to be thinking about.
每次我問這個問題，
Every time I ask this question
我通常會得到不錯的答案，有時是立刻的，
I usually get a good answer, sometimes immediately
有時人們需要更久的時間來思考。
sometimes it takes longer for people to think about that.
我想問你最喜歡的提示語是什麼，
I want to ask about your favorite prompts
那些你用過能帶來有趣結果的東西，
things that you've used that give you fun results
或是很酷的使用方式。
or cool ways to use it.
所以我注意到兩件事。
So I've kind of noticed two things.
我覺得最主要的是我真的可以，
I think the main thing is I can really.
我可以稍微個人化，
I can kind of personalize
並且告訴 ChatGPT 關於我的具體資訊，
and give Chachi BT the specifics about me
然後讓它根據那些給我一個答案。
and and then have it give me an answer based on that.
所以我告訴它我的飲食偏好，還有我
So I tell it my diet preferences, what I
對我吃的食物有什麼期望。
what I want out of the food that I'm eating.
當我去超市時，
And when I go to the grocery store
我會拍下收據，讓它幫我評分。
I'll take a picture of the receipt and have it grade it.
你知道，我做得如何？
You know, how well did I do?
根據這次購物行程，
Based on this grocery trip
因為我想確保
because I want to make sure
我有攝取到所有的維生素。
that I highlight and I get all my vitamins.
假設這是我特定的目標，
And let's say that's my specific goal
它會根據這點客觀地給我評分。
and it'll grade me based on that objectively.
而且它還會追蹤我的進展。
And it also track progress over time.
但我認為，提示的重點是
But I think the the main thing with with prompts is
你可以談論你自己，
that you can talk about you yourself
而且它會把這些存進記憶中。
and it also store that in memory.
我打籃球已經很久了，
So I, I've been playing basketball for a long time,
幾乎是我一生中大部分時間。
almost all my life.
我遇到了一些膝蓋的問題。
And I have like some knee issues that I've run into.
有時候傳統的、所謂最好的腿部鍛鍊方式，
And sometimes the traditional, like, best way to, like
對我來說並不適合。
work out your legs isn't the best.
當你膝蓋疼痛時，
When you have knee pain
每個人的疼痛類型和誘發方式都不同，
and everyone has different types of pain and different ways
會有不同的加劇原因。
that that gets aggravated.
所以當我問Chachi BT時，
So when I ask Chachi BT, you know
我有這個疼痛，
I have this pain
但做這個動作時感覺沒問題，
but when I do this exercise, it feels fine
做這個動作時卻很痛。
but when I do this exercise, it really hurts.
你能幫我嗎？
So can you make me?
你能幫我診斷問題嗎？
Can you maybe diagnose the problem?
也許它不太擅長這方面。
Maybe it's not that good at that
但你能幫我做嗎？
but can you make me?
只是一個圍繞我特定需求設計的運動計劃嗎？
Just a exercise regimen that'll be wrapped around my specific needs.?
那真的很酷
That's really cool
讓我有了一些想法。
giving me some ideas.
我覺得對我來說。
I think for me.
所以我也能想到兩個使用情境。
So I also can think of like two use cases.
但我個人認為
But I think personally for me
最棒的事情是，
the best thing that you know.
ChatGPT 和 AI 給我的，是時間，還有
Chachi BT and like AI gives me is like, time, and like
我覺得有更多時間會讓我快樂。
I think having more time makes me happy.
所以我覺得 ChatGPT 確實讓我這個人更快樂。
So like, I feel like Chachi BT does make me happy as a person.
但我認為這種快樂最好的展現是，
But I think the best kind of like manifestation of that is like,
像是日常生活中一些小事。
kind of like small, day-to-day tasks.
我記得有一次我用它是因為
And I think one of the times I used it was so
我想我有一個閱讀清單，
I think I had like a reading list of
我想去買大約15本書。
like 15 books that I wanted to go get.
我校園附近最近的書店是最後一本書店，
And so the nearest bookstore from my campus is the last bookstore
它位於洛杉磯市中心。
which is in DTLA.
對於不在洛杉磯或不熟悉這區域的人來說，
And for those of you who aren't from LA or know the area
停車非常困難。
it's really tough on parking.
這裡的停車情況很緊湊，進出都很快。
It's kind of like a very in and out situation.
所以我感受到時間上的壓力。
So I think there's like a time pressure for me.
我也不想付四十美元的停車費。
And I also didn't want to pay like 40 bucks.
到了某個時候，
After a certain point.
我想要制定一個最佳策略，讓我能夠進入，
I wanted to put together, you know, the optimal strategy to get in
並在15分鐘內離開書店。
and out of the bookstore in like 15 minutes.
所以我先把資料輸入，
And so that started off with kind of feeding it.
像是我心中想買的那15本書，
Like the 15 books that I had in mind
並根據，
and organize it based off of,
圖書館的分類系統來整理，
like, the library's organization system,
然後是該類型作者的姓氏。
and then the last name of the authors in the genre.
所以，大概就是這三個輸入。
So, like, kind of, like those three inputs.
它給了我最優化的策略，讓我能夠
And so it gave me the most optimal strat to kind of like,
盡快拿到那些書然後離開。
grab those books and get out as fast as possible.
我覺得這是一個很酷的應用案例。
So I thought that was a really cool use case.
而且我一直在使用，
And I've been using, you know,
很多類似的應用來優化我的時間。
a lot of kind of use cases like that to optimize my time.
然後還有另一個應用案例，
And then just another kind of like use case.
其實是我朋友教我的，
That actually my friend taught me is to kind of
利用語音模式來幫助節省時間。
use voice mode to really also help with that time convenience.
我看到他開車時使用它，
And so I saw him use it while he was driving
他開啟了語音模式。
and he put it on voice mode.
每次他看到舊金山的科技廣告牌，
And every time he would see, like a tech billboard in San Francisco
他就會問，喔，
he would ask it, Oh
這是什麼公司？這個廣告牌是什麼意思？
what is this company? like? what does this billboard mean?
我覺得他能夠這樣做很不錯，
So I think it was nice how he's able
邊做邊學，然後就像是
to kind of learn on the go and just like
做一些他感興趣的事情。
do some things that he's like interested in with.
像是開車這種平凡的任務。
Kind of like mundane tasks like driving.
所以我也開始嘗試這樣做。
And then so I started kind of adopting that.
我現在正在上暑期課程，
I'm taking like a summer course right now
所以沒有太多時間，
and so I don't have a lot of time with,
你知道的，工作、通勤和開車，
you know, the work, commute while driving
而且大部分時間都在工作。
and then there's actual work for most of my day.
所以為了真正有效利用時間，
So to really optimize my time
我一直用語音模式來進行，
I've been just asking, using voice mode to kind of do like,
穩定地反覆回顧某些概念。
steady, like, recall and back and forth on certain concepts.
這樣當我回到家時，
So that when I get home
我覺得我的大腦已經準備好並且活躍，
I feel like my brain is already ready and active to like,
可以開始做作業。
do the assignments.
我覺得這一點真的很酷，
So I think like that aspect has been really cool,
能夠使用語音功能也非常棒。
and being able to use that voice feature is also really cool.
因為它驚人地像真人一樣。
Because it's scarily like, human like.
所以我感覺自己真的在跟人對話。
So I feel like I'm actually talking to someone.
大家真的很棒。
Guys has been great.
感謝你們兩位的到來，
I thank you both for being here
期待未來能再度交談，
and look forward to talking again further down
看看你們各自的路走向何方。
and seeing where your paths have taken you.
不，真的非常感謝你邀請我們。
Yeah, no, thank you so much for having us.
我覺得這是一個很棒的平台，可以談論，
I feel like it's a great platform to kind of like talk about,
像是人工智慧，還有
like AI and like
特別是在教育領域，
especially in the education space
因為這是非常重要的議題。
because something's so salient.
所以我很高興，像是，
So I'm glad, like, you know
我們有這個平台讓我們聚在一起。
we had this platform for having us.
是的，可以用像這樣的詞語。
Yeah, can use words like.
突出，我贊同她的說法，不，這是。
Salient, I echo what she said, No, this is.
這真是一次很棒的對話。
This has been great, great conversation.
我很高興我們能談論
I'm glad we got to talk about
一些尖銳的議題，也有一些樂觀的話題。
some hard-hitting topics and also some optimistic topics.
是的，我非常樂觀。
Yeah, I'm very optimistic.
我的意思是，這將會是。
I mean, it's gonna be.
我們越能幫助朋友適應
The more we can help our friends adapt
並找到自己的定位，就越好。
and find their own place with it, the better.